Guide to the Brooks Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Harold Allen Brooks, Jr. Research, 1899-2001; Series IV
  - Jeanneret, Charles-Edouard [Le Corbusier]
    - Early Professional Career, 1912-1916 [Section III of Le Corbusier's Formative Years ]
      - Photographs
        - France [architectural projects and executed work], 1917-1920 (Box 98)
        - Painting, 1911-1919 (Box 98)
        - Executed Work, 1916
          - La Scala cinema (Box 99)
          - Villa Schwob
            - Designs and plans (Box 99)
            - Exteriors (Box 99)
            - Sources (Box 99)
            - Interiors and construction photographs (Box 99)
            - Photocopies (Box 99)
    - Postscript [1917-1920; Section IV of Le Corbusier's Formative Years ]
      - Correspondence
        - Outgoing to parents
          - Photocopies of originals, 1917-1920 (Box 100)
          - Typed transcriptions of originals [2 folders], 1913, 1917-1920 (Box 100)
          - Citations, 1899-1927 (Box 100)
        - Ritter, William [photocopies of originals and typed transcriptions of originals], 1917-1924 (Box 100)
        - Perrin, Léon, 1918, 1920 (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous, post-1920 (Box 100)
    - Interviews with individuals who knew Jeanneret
      - Sert, JoséLuis
        - Typed transcription, 1980 November (Box 100)
        - Portion of H. A. Brooks, Jr. lecture, "Jeanneret: Paris & Purism", 1978 February 22, 1980 November 15; 1 (Box 101)
      - Perriand, Charlotte, 1976 April 12; 1 (Box 102)
      - Montmollin, Jean-Pierre de, 1974 February 16; 1 (Box 103)
      - Montandon, Marcel (side 1) and M. Pierre Hirsch (side 2), 1975 November; 1 (Box 104)
        - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 104D)
      - Perrin, Léon, 1975 October 31; 1 (Box 105)
        - Use copies, 2 (Box 105Ua–105Ub)
      - Chapallaz, René, 1973 October 22; 1 (Box 106)
    - Le Corbusier Parle: Mes Pensées à 73 Ans, audiocassette, 1960; 1 (Box 107)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 108)
    - Black-line prints of Jeanneret buildings and drawings, 1908, 1916, undated (Box 109)
    - Notecard files [handwritten; alphabetically arranged by topic], undated (Box 110–111)
- Additional Material, 1963-1998; Accession 2006-M-117
  - List of H. Allen Brooks's publications, undated (Box 1)
  - Short writings by H. Allen Brooks regarding Charles-Edouard Jeanneret (Le Corbusier) and the Prairie School architects [articles, book reviews, and reviews of Brooks's books; includes printed materials, reprints, clippings, and drafts], 1963-1998 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1923-2006, undated; Accession 2011-M-025
  - Personal, 2004, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Architecture history, 1978-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale MA thesis, "Leopold Eidlitz, 1823-1908", 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ph.D. dissertation, "The Prairie School, The American Spirit in Midwest Residential Architecture, 1893-1916", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1923-2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Presentation drawing by Andrew Euston of the Brooks residence, 1939 (Box 2)
    This presentation drawing by Euston was made after the architect's first visit to the site in the spring of 1939, the house being designed and built almost exactly as shown. Included is a writing by H. Allen Brooks as to why he became an architectural historian as it relates to this drawing.